Peter Young

San Francisco, CA | pspyoung2@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I am a Full Stack Developer with an MA in Sport Psychology. I studied Sport Psychology to learn how people perform at their best, and transferred those skills in Social Work to solve everyday problems. After three-years of reacting to similar crises, I wanted a more technically challenging career. Instead of applying band-aids, I wanted to proactively create meaningful solutions. That's when I discovered and fell in love with coding. I enjoy the technical challenge, the immediate feedback of knowing when the code works, and creating tangible results. My code is similar to my work with people: looking at the application or person as a whole, with great attention to detail, and with the client's best interest at heart.

TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Mongo, JSON

Libraries and Frameworks: React, Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap, Bulma, Material UI

Databases and other: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful Routing, JSON API

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

pongScores - <u>GitHub</u> | <u>App</u> - JavaScript, MongoDB/Mongoose.js, Express, React, Node.js, MaterialUI App that allows users to add, edit, and keep track of players' Table Tennis match records.

- Created an app with full CRUD functionality on front end and back end.
- Lists players through drop down bars. All player and match data automatically update to the backend.

Pomodoro App - GitHub | App - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB/Mongoose.js, Express, React, Node.js *Pomodoro app that keeps track of study and break timers and updates user input tasks.*

- Created a single page app with a visual countdown timer that automatically switches between task and break.
- Timer task data is created and edited on the application page and data gets sent to the backend.

Clash Royale Cards API - GitHub | App - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React

Gives users a lightweight and easy-to-use access app to research Clash Royale card stats.

- Built a multi-page application that categorizes types of cards that have links to additional information.
- Gathered data from the RoyaleAPI to list all information about cards

I'm Beary Excited! - GitHub | App_- JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bulma

A tamogotchi type game, where the user keeps the bear alive while watching it grow. Bad bear puns included.

- Created visual timer bars that decrease automatically and increase with user clicks.
- Initiated Victory Game Over, and Game Stage messages triggered when conditions are met.

EXPERIENCE

Mercy Housing, Resident Service Coordinator, San Francisco, CA

07/2019 - 09/2021

• Provided and connected residents with community resources that allows them to safely age in place.

SteppingStone Adult Day Health Care, Social Worker, San Francisco, CA

07/2018 - 06/2019

• Created care plans, conducted regular assessments, and provided services so seniors can live safely at home.

Outreach Coordinator*, 04/2018 - 07/2018

• Contributed to marketing strategy, and spearheaded email blasts to 10,000 healthcare professionals.

Social Work Assistant,

09/2016 - 07/2018

• Conducted intake, outreach, organized community events, and assisted with updating care plans.

Table Tennis Club, Mental Skills Coach, Bay Area, San Francisco,

09/2016 - 06/2017

• Held mental skills workshops, and provided mental coaching to improve athletes' performance.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Coding Bootcamp, Certificate, Remote,	04/2022
John F. Kennedy University, Masters of Arts, Sport Psychology, Pleasant Hill, California	09/2017
University of California, Davis, Bachelors of Arts, Psychology, Davis, California	12/2015